According to textual evidence, Confucius compiled the Six Classics (Liu Jing) during his later years in the state of Lu,
and we all are very familiar with these books.
They are known as Shi Jing (Book of Odes), Shu Jing (Book of History), Li Jing (Book of Rites), Yuejing (Book of Music, now lost), Yi Jing (Book of Changes) and Chun Qiu (Spring and Autumn Annals).
Confucius used these Classics as teaching materials for his students.
One of these books, the Li Jing,
has been known since the Han dynasty as the Yi Li (Book of Etiquette and Ceremonial).
This book has a total of seventeen sections
covering the rites for occasions such as coming-of-age, marriage,
drinking ceremonies, archery competitions, and so forth.
Of these, the Rites of the Provincial Archery Competition
is our focus in a project to re-enact the rites and
to rekindle an understanding of the rites’ true significance.
Firstly
not only in China itself
but in the entire world
it is the earliest recorded form of archery competition
for which a complete textual description exists.
Previously, a number of international authorities in the field
have claimed that the earliest archery competition
was invented by the British nobility in the 14th century CE;
but our text dates from the late Spring and Autumn period.
From inscriptions on bronze vessels we know
that it existed much earlier in China;
in fact as early as the 8th century BCE
archery competitions were being held in China,
The archery tradition in China is vastly different from that of the West
for in China archery was designed as
a method of moral cultivation
in which one learns how to respect one’s opponent
and how to handle defeat.
This principle is called  “If one does not hit the target, he should seek the cause within himself.”
By re-staging this kind of competition we seek to establish their attitude
of how to approach one’ s life;
how to handle one’s affairs;
how to improve one’s performance.
When the Chinese archery competition later was transmitted to Korea
and to Japan
they also felt that there was a special kind of philosophy within it,
and so they did not call it the Rite of Archery
but rather the Way of the Bow (Kyudo)
believing that there was a guiding philosophical principle behind the bow and arrow
and that they have an extremely positive significance for human development.
This concept is also found in the Analects of Confucius
which describes how during the archery competition the gentlemen would
“bow and yield the way to each as they ascend to the hall, and drink a salute as they descend from the hall.”
Confucius called this “a competition of exemplary persons”.
It demonstrates how in the East such kind of competition
carries within a very deep and rich civilizational connotation.
Through this re-enactment we
hope that many friends
will find enjoyment in the Confucian Rite of Archery
and will themselves take part
in order to personally experience its humanist significance.